Eva Heinemann?
Eva Heinemann mı?
Yeah, she was here.
Evet, buradaydı.
She's fallen on pretty hard times, but her attitude is as bad as before.
Çok zor dönemler geçirdi ve tavrı her zamanki gibi çok kötü.
I think it's gotten even worse.
Sanırım daha da kötüleşti.
Did she say where she's staying?
Nerede kaldığını söyledi mi?
She said she didn't have any cash with her,
Üzerinde nakit olmadığını,
She still thinks she's a princess.
Kendini hâlâ prenses sanıyor.
Which hotel is it?
Hangi otel?
I think she said it was Hotel Staigent.
Sanırım Hotel Staigent dedi.
If she's staying at a third-rate hotel like that, I doubt I'll ever get paid.
Öyle üç yıldızlı bir otelde kalıyorsa paramı alacağımı hiç sanmıyorum.
Wait…
Dur…
Aren't you the guy who was engaged to her?
Sen onun nişanlısı değil misin?
I'm sure of it!
Bundan eminim!
Hello? Police? That guy wanted for murder was just here.
Alo. Polis mi?
-Hey! -Huh?
-Hey. -Ne?
Where's my coat?
Kabanım nerede?
I hung it on the rack by the door.
Kapının yanındaki askılığa asmıştım.
Hello?
Alo.
I think there's a woman named Eva Heinemann staying at your hotel.
Sanırım otelinizde Eva Heinemann adında bir kişi kalıyor.
Yes. I'll connect you to her room.
Evet, odasına bağlıyorum.
Hold on a moment.
Bir saniye bekleyin.
Thanks.
Teşekkürler.
CREDIT: DM 300
KREDİ: 300 ALMAN MARKI
Hurry.
Çabuk ol.
CREDIT: DM 150
150 ALMAN MARKI
Hurry!
Çabuk ol!
I think I'm going to kill…
Yani sanırım
your ex-fiancée, Eva Heinemann.
eski nişanlın Eva Heinemann'ı öldüreceğim.
Hurry up!
Çabuk ol!
Thank you for waiting.
Beklediğiniz için teşekkürler. Odasını aradım ama açmadı.
What's her room number?
Oda numarası kaç?
I want to send her a fax, so could you give me her room number?
Ona faks göndermek istiyorum, oda numarasını verebilir misiniz?
Please, tell me.
Lütfen söyle.
Her room number is 402.
Oda numarası 402.
Our fax number is…
Faks numaramız da…
402…
402.
It's no good.
Olmuyor.
Mr. Baul's not in his office and isn't answering his phone either.
Bay Baul ofisinde değil ve telefonuna da cevap vermiyor.
I doubt your partner will show up no matter how long we wait.
Ne kadar beklersek bekleyelim partnerinin geleceğini düşünmüyorum.
And this is why I think so.
Böyle düşünme sebebim de şu,
He became Tenma's lawyer to prove his innocence.
Tenma'nın masumiyetini kanıtlamak için onun avukatı oldu
But then Tenma confessed to everything, and to make things worse, he escaped.
ama Tenma her şeyi itiraf edince işleri batırdı, avukat da kaçtı.
He probably thinks there's no way he can defend Tenma,
Tenma'yı asla savunamayacağını düşünüyordur.
so he's dropping him as his client.
Bu yüzden onu temsil etmeyi bırakıyor.
Will you drop him too, Mr. Verdemann?
Sen de bırakacak mısın Vendemann?
No, I won't.
Hayır, bırakmayacağım.
However, Tenma has now escaped.
Ama Tenma kaçtı.
I wish he had trusted me to help him before he escaped.
Keşke kaçmadan önce ona yardım edebileceğime inansaydı.
So you believe in Tenma?
Yani Tenma'ya inanıyor musun?
Do you believe what happened in Munich?
Münih'te olanlara inanıyor musun?
Do you believe everything that Tenma told me?
Tenma'nın bana anlattığı her şeye inanıyor musun?
Do you know what I think?
Ne düşünüyorum biliyor musun? Bence bunların hiçbirine inanmıyorsun.
When I heard the news of Tenma's escape, it felt the same as what happened before.
Tenma'nın kaçtığı haberini duyduğumda
It felt like when he disappeared in Munich to go and assassinate Johan.
Johan'ı öldürmek için Münih'te kaybolduğu anda
There's something he's trying to do.
Bir şey yapmaya çalışıyor.
That's why Tenma escaped!
Tenma bu yüzden kaçtı.
Believe in him!
Ona inan.
Believe in him like you did your father, which led you to become a lawyer.
Babana inandığın gibi ona da inan. Avukat olmanı buna borçlusun.
The phone's been ringing off the hook!
Telefonlar susmak bilmiyor.
The media's going crazy asking
Medya delirdi, büyük avukat Verdemann'ın
if the great attorney Verdemann will continue to defend Tenma.
Tenma'yı savunmaya devam edip etmeyeceğini soruyorlar.
Tell them that I have no comment.
Yorum yapmayacağımı söyle.
But we can't keep the press at bay for long just saying that.
Ama böyle diyerek medyayı fazla tutamayız.
Then tell them we'll hold a press conference
O zaman bu davadaki her gelişmeyi inceledikten sonra
after I've reviewed all the facts in this case again.
basın toplantısı düzenleyeceğimizi söyle.
Until then, don't let anyone into the office.
O ana dek ofisime kimse girmesin.
But you already got a visitor.
Ama bir ziyaretçiniz var.
You're kidding?
Şaka mı yapıyorsun?
You let them in?
İçeri mi aldın?
I'm not seeing anyone today!
Bugün randevum yok.
I know. I told him so and tried to turn him away,
Biliyorum, bunu söyleyip onu reddetmeye çalıştım
Who the heck is it?
Kim lan bu?
He's from the Federal Police.
-Federal Polisten. -Federal Kriminal Polis Ofisi
"Over the Rainbow."
"Gökkuşağının Ardında"
Such a lovely song.
Çok hoş bir şarkı.
If I'm not mistaken, it was the theme song of your father's radio station.
Yanılmıyorsam babanızın radyo kanalının jenerik müziğiydi.
Who are you?
Siz kimsiniz?
My name is Lunge.
Adım Lunge.
406.
406.
405.
405.
404.
404.
Room 402.
402. oda.
That's the room.
Odası orada.
Guten tag.
İyi günler.
-Excuse me. -What?
-Pardon. -Efendim?
Where's the guest staying in this room?
Bu odada kalan kişi nerede?
Who?
Kim?
I've come to visit the guest staying here.
Burada kalan kişiyi ziyarete geldim.
Huh? Haven't they already checked out?
Ne? Çoktan çıkış yapmadı mı o?
See? There's nobody here.
Bakın, burada kimse yok.
Eva…
Eva.
Inspector Lunge.
Dedektif Lunge.
I've looked through many of Tenma's police statement records.
Tenma'nın ifade kayıtlarının çoğunu inceledim.
Yours was one of those that I had a careful look at.
Sizinkini dikkatlice inceledim.
It was an extremely detailed report.
Son derece detaylı bir rapordu.
I've also heard rumors about you, the darling of the legal world,
Hakkınızda söylentileri de duydum. Hukuk camiasının sevilen yüzü
Mr. Verdemann.
Bay Verdemann.
I'm sure you came to me after hearing about Tenma's escape.
Tenma'nın kaçtığını duyduktan sonra bana geldiğinize eminim.
Unfortunately,
Ne yazık ki
I have absolutely no information about it that I can offer you.
bu konuda elimde size verebileceğim hiçbir bilgi yok.
He escaped, huh?
Kaçtı demek.
I'm in the middle of an extended vacation right now.
Şu an uzun bir tatilin ortasındayım.
You could even call this long vacation an escape of sorts for me too.
Bu tatile benim için de bir kaçış diyebilirsiniz.
You'll have to excuse me, but I don't have time for small talk.
Kusura bakmayın ama hoşbeş edecek vaktim yok.
Probably out of habit from working for so many years,
Bunca sene çalışmanın getirdiği bir alışkanlık galiba.
I cannot take a vacation without any specific purpose.
Belli bir amacı olmadan bir tatile çıkamıyorum.
So I've developed a sort of theme for my vacation.
Tatilim için bir tür tema uydurdum.
The theme for this vacation is this picture book.
Bu tatilin teması da bu resimli kitap.
I'm sorry, but I don't have time for this.
Üzgünüm ama buna ayıracak vaktim yok.
I'd like you to leave.
Gitmenizi istiyorum.
Let's talk a little longer.
Biraz daha konuşalım.
I told you, I have nothing to say about Tenma.
Tenma hakkında diyecek bir şeyim yok dedim.
I have not come here to talk about Tenma.
Tenma hakkında konuşmaya gelmedim.
You see,
Tenma'nın kaçtığını buraya gelirken yolda duydum.
Then why in the world are you here?
-O zaman ne diye geldiniz? -Dediğim gibi, bu resimli kitap için.
I am deeply interested in learning more about the author of this book.
Bu kitabın yazarını bir hayli merak ediyorum
However, the author had several pen names.
ama yazarın birden fazla takma adı varmış.
The only one he used that was German is Klaus Poppe.
Kullandığı tek Alman ismi Klaus Poppe.
That intrigued me, so when I looked into it,
Bu da ilgimi çekti, araştırdım
I found that there was a certain person who Poppe was associated with.
ve Poppe'yle ilişkisi olan bir kişi olduğunu öğrendim.
What person was that?
Kimmiş o?
Your father.
Babanız.
Your father's radio station ran a show called Fairy Tales of the World.
Babanızın radyo kanalında Dünyanın Masalları adlı bir program vardı.
According to records, in August 1966, Poppe's work Where Am I? was aired.
Kayıtlara göre 1966'nın ağustos ayında
I had a look at the records of your father's trial as well,
Babanızın duruşma kayıtlarına da baktım.
the greatest post-war espionage case. A case that shook all of West Germany.
Savaş sonrası en büyük casusluk davası. Batı Almanya'yı tümden sarsan bir dava.
So, what about it?
Ne olmuş yani?
Your father traveled to Czechoslovakia several times.
Babanız birkaç kez Çekoslovakya'ya gitti.
Since they were just meetings with a picture book author,
Sadece resimli kitap yazarlarıyla görüştüğü için
the prosecutor never mentioned them.
savcı bunlardan hiç bahsetmedi.
What are you implying?
Ne ima ediyorsunuz?
It seems to me that your father was old friends with this picture book author.
Görünüşe göre babanız bu resimli kitap yazarıyla eski dostmuş.
Due to his line of work, my father had lots of connections.
Mesleği gereği babamın pek çok bağlantısı vardı.
He met with an infinite number of people for his show.
Programı için bir sürü insanla tanıştı.
Are you saying that he wasn't a close acquaintance with Poppe?
Poppe'yle yakın arkadaş olmadığını mı söylüyorsunuz?
However, I looked into it.
Ama bunu araştırdım.
Ordinarily, Klaus Poppe had meetings either at his editor's home
Klaus Poppe toplantılarını genelde editörünün evinde
or at an old farmhouse that served as his villa in the Czech suburbs.
veya Çek banliyölerinde villa olarak kullandığı
But when your father met him, they met at a certain mansion.
Ama babanız onunla bir malikânede buluştu.
A mansion?
Malikânede mi?
It was called the Red Rose Mansion.
Adı Kırmızı Güllü Malikâne.
But he never met people at that mansion using the name Klaus Poppe.
Ama o malikânede görüştüğünde asla Klaus Poppe ismini kullanmadı.
When he used that mansion, the name he used was…
O malikâneye gittiğinde kullandığı isim
Franz Bonaparta.
Franz Bonaparta'ydı.
He held a very important post in the Czechoslovakia secret police.
Çekoslovakya gizli polisinde çok önemli bir konuma sahipti.
What…
Ne…
What are you implying?
Ne ima ediyorsunuz?
Son of a spy!
Casusun oğlu!
You're the son of a traitor!
Bir hainin oğlusun sen!
You son of a coward!
Ödleğin oğlusun!
Hey! If you don't like it, then prove that he didn't do it!
Hey! Hoşuna gitmiyorsa onun yapmadığını kanıtla o zaman!
If the father's scum, then his son is too!
Babası pislikse oğlu da pisliktir!
Son of a spy!
Casusun oğlu!
I simply want to know about the man Franz Bonaparta.
Franz Bonaparta adlı bu adam hakkında bilgi almak istiyorum sadece.
I don't know him!
Onu tanımıyorum!
Your father met with the author Klaus Poppe at a certain mansion
Babanız, Klaus Poppe adlı yazarla 1966'da, Çekoslovakya'da
in Czechoslovakia in 1966.
bir malikânede buluştu.
Their only connection is as a picture book author
Sadece bir resimli kitap yazarı
When he used the name Klaus Poppe,
Klaus Poppe ismi altında
he never once used the Red Rose Mansion.
Kırmızı Güllü Malikâne'yi bir kez bile kullanmadı.
What are you implying?
Ne ima ediyorsunuz?
If your father met with that man at the Red Rose Mansion,
Babanız o adamla Kırmızı Güllü Malikâne'de buluştuysa
then the man he met with wasn't Klaus Poppe,
buluştuğu adam Klaus Poppe olamaz.
but it was Franz Bonaparta, the man who held
O adam Çekoslovakya gizli polisinde önemli bir konuma sahip olan
These are false accusations!
Bunların hepsi iftira!
I don't care at all whether your father was a spy or not.
Babanızın casus olup olmaması hiç umurumda değil!
My father was no spy!
Babam casus değildi!
I'm sure your father was aware of exactly who Franz Bonaparta was.
Franz Bonaparta'nın kim olduğunu babanızın bildiğine adım gibi eminim.
How is that relevant?
Ne alakası var?
I think you know what your father did when he went
Babanızın Kırmızı Güllü Malikâne'ye gittiğinde ne yaptığını biliyorsunuz.
No! You're wrong!
Hayır, yanılıyorsun!
My father is innocent! You're wrong!
Babam masum! Yanılıyorsun!
You're wrong!
Yanılıyorsun!
Please contact me when you feel like talking.
Konuşmak istediğinizde lütfen bana ulaşın.
Let me repeat
Tekrar edeyim,
that I have no interest whatsoever in whether or not your father was a spy.
babanızın casus olup olmamasıyla hiç mi hiç ilgilenmiyorum.
All I want to know is anything relating to Franz Bonaparta.
Tek istediğim Franz Bonaparta'yla ilgili bilgi almak.
My father…
Babam…
Mr. Verdemann, your wife is on the phone.
Bay Verdemann, karınız telefonda.
Is there something wrong?
Bir sorun mu var?
No.
Hayır.
Your wife is on the phone. She's calling from the maternity ward.
Karınız telefonda. Doğumhaneden arıyor.
Right.
Evet.
Hello?
Alo.
Is that right? You've been discharged? That's great.
Öyle mi? Taburcu mu edildin? Harika bir haber bu.
Okay, got it. I'll head right over.
Tamam, anladım. Hemen geliyorum.
-Tenma! -Start driving!
-Tenma! -Hemen sür!
Calm down! Listen to me!
Sakin ol, beni dinle!
Start driving right now!
Hemen sür!
Now!
Hemen!
Let's talk this over.
Konuşalım şu işi.
Just calm down and tell me why you're doing this.
Sakin ol ve bunu neden yaptığını anlat.
Where's Eva?
Eva nerede?
Where's Eva Heinemann?
Eva Heinemann nerede?
What are you talking about?
Neden bahsediyorsun?
What's Eva Heinemann got to do with this?
Eva Heinemann'ın ne ilgisi var?
Don't play dumb!
Numara yapma! Sizin ne yapmaya çalıştığınızı biliyorum!
"You people"?
Bizim mi?
Don't stop the car! Eyes forward and keep driving!
Arabayı durdurma! Önüne bak ve sürmeye devam et!
I know you people want to take Eva's life!
Sizin Eva'yı öldürmek istediğinizi biliyorum!
"Take Eva's life"? What do you mean by "you people"?
Eva'yı öldürmek mi? Siz derken kimi kastediyorsun?
Don't play dumb!
Numara yapma!
You and that partner of yours who calls himself Baul are in cahoots.
Adının Baul olduğunu söyleyen ortağınla iş birliği içindesiniz!
Baul?
Baul mu?
He's the man I shot at the library at Munich University!
Münih Üniversitesi kütüphanesinde vurduğum adam o.
I can't let anyone else die!
Başka kimsenin ölmesine izin veremem!
Tell me where you've taken Eva!
Eva'yı nereye götürdüğünü söyle!
This all started when I saved Johan's life.
Her şey Johan'ın hayatını kurtarmamla başladı.
So many people have died since then.
O zamandan sonra bir sürü insan öldü.
So many, many people!
Hem de bir sürü.
I can't take it anymore! I can't let anyone else die!
Artık dayanamıyorum! Başkasının ölmesine izin veremem!
Don't stop the car!
Arabayı durdurma!
Is that true?
Doğru mu?
I said drive!
Sür dedim!
Is what you said just now true?
Anlattıkların doğru mu?
Can I believe it's the truth?
Doğru olduğuna inanabilir miyim?
My father was convicted of being a spy.
Babam casusluktan hüküm yedi.
Later, he was exonerated.
Daha sonra aklandı.
But the truth is, he was a spy.
Ama işin aslı o bir casustu.
Because I believed my father was innocent,
Babamın masum olduğuna inandığım için
I chose to be a lawyer and studied very hard.
avukat olmayı seçip çok çalıştım
But I found something when I was in university.
ama üniversitedeyken bir şey buldum.
I found irrefutable evidence that my father was a spy.
Babamın casus olduğuna dair inkâr edilemeyecek bir delil buldum.
Ever since then…
O zamandan beri…
Ever since then, I couldn't believe anyone anymore.
O zamandan beri artık kimseye inanamıyorum.
Me, the lawyer who gets his clients exonerated!
Müvekkillerinin adını temizleyen ben!
Me, the darling of the legal world!
Hukuk dünyasının sevilen ismi!
What a joke! They've been fooled by a man who doesn't believe anyone!
Tam bir fiyasko! Kimseye inanmayan adam hepsini kandırdı!
You see…
Biliyor musun,
I was the son of a spy.
bir casusun oğluydum.
When I found his notebook…
Babamın 1960'larda…
When I found the notebook my father wrote in the 1960s.
Babamın 1960'larda yazdığı defteri bulduğumda…
As I turned the pages and read what was written in it,
Yazılanları sayfa sayfa okurken
everything I'd built on my belief in my father just crumbled away.
babama dair inandığım her şey yerle bir oldu.
My father had, without a doubt, been a spy.
Babam casustu. Ona hiç şüphe yok.
It was filled with an indecipherable code.
Kırılması imkânsız şifrelerle doluydu.
A record of his numerous meetings with the Czechoslovakia secret police.
Çekoslovakya gizli polisiyle yaptığı sayısız görüşmesinin bir kaydı.
My father met many mysterious people, including Franz Bonaparta.
Babam bir sürü gizemli insanla görüştü, bunlara Franz Bonaparta da dâhil.
Did he also write about the Red Rose Mansion?
Kırmızı Güllü Malikâne'yi de yazmış mı?
How did you know about that?
Bunu nereden biliyorsun?
So, that's why.
Bu yüzden demek…
That man Baul probably approached you
Baul denen o adam o defteri almak istediği için
Where is that notebook now?
O defter şu an nerede?
At my house.
Evimde.
What a mess.
Darmadağın.
There's no doubt about it now.
Hiç şüphe yok.
He was after your father's notebook.
Babanın defterinin peşindeymiş.
DEAR KENZO
SEVGİLİ KENZO
It's a letter for you.
Sana mektup bırakmış.
He must have figured that you would come here.
Buraya geleceğini anlamış olmalı.
"Save me, Kenzo. Save me, Kenzo!
"Kurtar beni Kenzo.
Come to the Red Rose Mansion quickly."
Hemen Kırmızı Güllü Malikâne'ye gel"
Does it mean Eva's safe?
Yani Eva güvende mi?
No.
Hayır.
This isn't her writing.
Bu onun el yazısı değil.
He's toying with me.
Benimle kafa buluyor.
That scum is toying with me!
Bu pislik benimle kafa buluyor!
It's still here.
Hâlâ burada.
It was among my pile of old records, inside "Over the Rainbow."
"Gökkuşağının Ötesinde"ki eski plaklarımın içindeydi.
This is the notebook.
Defter bu.
Take it.
Al.
But if it gets into anyone else's hands, the truth about your father will…
Ama birinin eline geçerse babanın gerçek kimliği…
I don't need this anymore.
Buna artık ihtiyacım yok.
FRÜHLING MATERNITY HOSPITAL
FRÜHLING DOĞUMEVİ
Can I believe you?
Sana inanabilir miyim?
What you've told me
Bana anlattıkların
and what you're about to go and do,
ve gidip yapacağın şeyler için
I can't help you with those.
sana yardım edemem.
But can I believe you, Dr. Tenma?
Ama sana inanabilir miyim Dr. Tenma?
Anyone who carries one of these things,
Silah taşıyan kimseye muhtemelen
you probably shouldn't believe.
hiç inanmamalısın.
I want to believe you.
Sana inanmak istiyorum.
Subtitle translation by: Brian Athey
Alt yazı çevirmeni: Ömür Gencer